So we’ve prepared
some compost materials,
so you guys can
try it yourselves.
I’ll partner up with Jao.
[JAO]
It's just amazing how...
the more I discover how
knowledgeable you are.
And I find your
intelligence...
very attractive.
[LEXI] Do you know
what that’s called?
[LEXI] Which, incidentally, is
happening right here, right now.
They've got chemistry, bro.
I’m Quinito.
Today’s story
is about...
Inoy.
On the island of Siargao,
he met many friends.
Goodbye,
my friend, pearl.
Do you like libraries?
You should see the
New York Public Library.
You’ve been to all the
libraries you mentioned?
You know, someone messaged me,
looking for a Song Ji Hoon.
[PEARL] Who’s that?
[KARA]
Sorry about Archie.
He’s a little blunt.
[LEXI]
I doubt it.
Well, since I'm leaving
anyway, whatever.
Bye, Kara!
[JAO] I like seeing
you like this, Kara.
The love you have for
Siargao is really inspiring.
I’m happy that
you’re here, Jao.
I’m thankful you came back.
- Does he smell good?
- [KARA LAUGHS]
Like baby powder?
Doesn’t he always look like
he smells like baby powder?
[CAROL STAMMERS]
- You go, girl! I’m proud of you!
- [KARA LAUGHS]
[JAO SPEAKS SIARGAONON]
Good morning.
[CAROL]
Hm?
[CAROL SNICKERING]
[CAROL AND KARA CHUCKLE]
[CAROL AND JAO CHUCKLE]
What’s the occasion?
Nothing. I just wanted
to give you flowers.
[JAO]
And don’t worry,
I asked permission from the
owner before I picked them.
- [KARA CHUCKLES]
- [CAROL GIGGLING]
Did you ask the plant, too?
- [JAO] Oh, man…
- [KARA CHUCKLES]
Just kidding.
Do we have plans today?
Not really.
Uh… here.
I just wanted to
make you breakfast.
And here.
It's just black coffee.
No sugar.
Thank you.
[CAROL CLEARS THROAT]
All right.
[JAO]
Hey!
Where are you going, Carol?
Aren’t you joining
us for breakfast?
[CAROL EXHALES]
Nope.
- I don’t want to get in the way.
- [JAO] Oh, please.
But I’ll take some Vitamin C to go.
[JAO AND KARA LAUGH]
[CAROL]
Smell you later!
- [JAO LAUGHS]
- [CAROL GIGGLES]
Should I pick you
up after your tour?
No, it’s okay!
When will I
see you again?
On...
Saturday!
Katig’s anniversary.
Saturday’s so far away.
[JAO]
How about this?
I'll drive you
around all day today,
so you can focus
on your tours.
Deal?
Jao, I’m not used
to being babied.
Nothing has to
change just because...
Okay.
Thank you.
I respect your timeline.
[JAO]
So...
I guess I’ll go talk
to the plant.
Go ahead.
[KARA LAUGHS]
[JAO LAUGHS]
Did you read the note?
“Smell me now,
dye me later”?
I put a lot of
thought into that.
- With a smiley?
- [JAO] Yes.
[ALON BY JL]
[HAN BIN EXHALES]
“Dear Admission Committee,”
"I’m writing…"
You smell so good, sir!
What?
You smell really fresh.
Like…
mint!
Oh, actually,
I have this very unique ritual
when I need to concentrate.
I always brush my teeth
before a brainstorming session.
It clears the mind.
Intense freshness gives focus.
You’re almost there, Pearl.
You have the right words.
You just need the
confidence to say it.
Well...
I will finish this
some other time.
I just need to get ready
for our celebration later.
But I’ll make sure to
brush my teeth first.
Okay.
Go ahead.
[PEARL CHUCKLES]
- It’s still warm!
- [ARIEL] It is!
[KARA]
Hold on!
- Hi, Kara!
- [KARA] It's aligned, right?
Ariel, give Kara a hand.
[ARIEL]
Okay, you got it!
- [PEARL] Oh, right! Hold on.
- [ARIEL] Wow!
[JAO]
Kara!
[CAROL]
Not like that!
[PEARL] Katig’s
anniversary should be fun!
[CAROL]
I hope they like it.
There you go!
[CAROL]
He likes this, right?
[HAN BIN]
Good morning, guys!
- [HAN BIN SPEAKS SIARGAONON] Morning!
- [PEOPLE] Morning!
- [PEARL] Hi, sir!
[JAO]
Happy anniversary!
Look, Jao.
- You haven't tried this yet, right?
- Cover it for now, Carol,
- before the flies get to it.
- [PEARL] There!
Yes!
I’m taking care of it.
- [PEARL] Let’s bring this outside, too.
- [CAROL] Leave it to me.
- [PEARL] Yes!
- [CAROL] Very good nice!
- [CAROL LAUGHS]
- [KARA] Later, we should...
- [PEARL] Let’s crush the peppers more.
- [CAROL] I agree. Like this.
- [PEARL] Yes!
- Need help?
- [PEARL] Wait, this is all that's left.
- I'm okay.
I'm just removing
the stray threads.
- [CAROL] Go ahead, open it.
- [PEARL] Wow! Yes!
- [HAN BIN] Peppers here.
- [PEARL] Yes.
You see this?
[KARA]
That’s because of you.
You see them?
[KARA] They all have
jobs because of you.
And you see this
crazy girl right here?
This crazy girl has
a job that she loves
and a business that
she’s passionate about
because of a
crazy guy like you.
[SIARGAONON]
Thank you very much, Han Bin.
[GUEST CHATTING]
Um...
That's fine.
This is good, too.
- [JAO] Need help?
- [PEARL] Hold on, we can just...
You guys all mean so much to me.
Thank you, Kara.
- I told you so.
- [ARIEL] Here, Jao.
- We'll fry that.
- [PEARL] It’s this one.
[JAO] Give it here so we
have room for the food.
[CAROL]
I'll put this here.
[PEARL]
Orange?
- [LOUD MUSIC PLAYING]
- [CROWD CHEERING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Wow!
[CROWD CHANTING]
[CROWD CHANTING AND LAUGHING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[JAO]
Let’s go!
[CROWD CHANTING]
- [ARIEL] Han Bin oppa!
- [CROWD CHEERING]
[JAO]
Mr. Han, come on!
[CROWD CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
[JAO]
Okay, next!
[CROWD GROANING]
[ARIEL] Guys, it’s just a power
outage. We’re used to that.
Let’s just turn
on our flashlights!
[JAO]
That works.
[ARIEL]
See? That's it.
Keep going!
- [CROWD CHANTING]
- [JAO] Keep going.
[CROWD CHANTING]
[JAO]
Let’s go!
[CROWD CHANTING]
[LOUD MUSIC RESUMES]
[CROWD CHEERING]
[JAO]
Wait!
- [PEARL] There!
- The party’s back on!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Yes!
- [PEARL] Kara! Kara!
- [ARIEL] Kara!
[CROWD]
Kara! Kara! Kara!
[JAO]
Smooth moves!
- [PEARL] Tantan!
- [ARIEL] Tantan!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[CROWD]
Tantan! Tantan! Tantan!
[CROWD LAUGHING]
[JAO]
Pearl!
[CROWD]
Go, Princess Pearl!
[CROWD CHANTING]
Princess Pearl! Princess Pearl!
[CROWD]
Lower! Lower! Lower!
[CROWD LAUGHING]
[JAO]
Who’s next? Ariel!
[CROWD CHANTING]
[PEARL]
Hey!
- [ARIEL GRUNTS]
- [CROWD LAUGH]
[JAO]
Just like his mother.
Definitely,
like mother, like son.
Like mother, like son.
Carla’s next!
[CROWD]
Carla! Carla! Carla!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Hey! It’s Quinito!
- Quinito!
- Hi, guys!
We miss you here!
- How’ve you been?
- [QUINITO] Don't say that.
You’re giving me FOMO.
[QUINITO CHUCKLES]
I mean, I hope to
see you guys soon.
Happy anniversary.
- Thank you!
- Bye!
- Come back, bro! We miss you!
- [QUINITO] Soon, brother. I promise.
- Bye! Take care!
- [QUINITO] Bye! Enjoy the party!
Bye.
[JAO]
Let’s keep it going.
[OVERLAPPING CHATTER]
Kara and Jao next!
[CROWD]
KaraJao! KaraJao! KaraJao!
[PEARL]
Lower!
[CROWD]
KaraJao! KaraJao! KaraJao!
[CROWD LAUGHING]
[JAO AND KARA LAUGH]
Tantan!
Bonfire, right?
- Bonfire, right?
Hey, Tantan.
Is this your kid?
Sir Jao...
Uh...
He's a street kid.
I usually give him food
whenever I see him.
So I brought him here.
Hope that’s okay.
Sure.
No problem.
Uh, Egay…
this is Sir Handsome.
You can also call him, Sir Jao.
Isn’t he handsome?
[JAO CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
You goofball.
Hi, Egay.
Have you eaten yet?
Tantan, can you please
get him something to eat?
- Okay, Sir Handsome.
- Thank you.
[SIARGAONON]
Your name’s Egay?
Tantan told me...
you don’t have
a place to stay.
- Where do you sleep?
- In a hut.
Where are you
from anyway?
Claver, Surigao.
Claver?
That’s pretty far.
That’s on another island, right?
Where are your parents?
My dad passed away.
- And your mom?
- She left me.
[SIARGAONON]
Where did she go?
I don’t know.
She just left.
How did you end
up here in Siargao?
My dad used to always
talk about Siargao.
He grew up here,
so I came here.
I’m staying here now.
My dad said
it’s beautiful here.
Isn’t your mom
looking for you?
Why would she?
She already left me.
I’m all alone.
But the people in
Surigao are kind.
They let me stay
in their homes.
And they give me food.
Like Uncle Tantan.
You’re not alone, Egay.
We’ll help you.
Starting today, you can
call me Uncle Jao, too.
Sounds good?
Do you go to school?
Do you want to?
Yes, sir.
I can help you go to school.
I’ll help you chase your dreams,
whatever they may be.
But you have to promise me
you’ll study hard.
You have to work hard
and stay disciplined.
And most importantly,
don’t give up.
No matter how
hard life gets...
No matter how cruel
the world can be...
don’t give up.
You’ll always have
people to help you.
- Pearl.
- Yeah?
Did you finish your
application form?
Thank you so much,
Sir Han, okay?
It’s just that…
I don’t know what to
talk about in my essay.
And also, the scholarship is…
a shot in the dark.
What do you mean?
[PEARL CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
It means impossible.
It’s impossible for me to…
[PEARL SIGHS]
…get accepted
into that university.
And also...
I’m scared.
I’m scared to do it.
I understand.
But there’s no
harm in trying, Pearl.
Just do it.
Do it even if it’s scary.
How about you?
Have you ever
tried something?
Or have you ever
tried doing something
that scared you?
Yes.
Many times.
- Really? Like what?
- Yeah.
Like…
skydiving in Dubai,
bungee jumping in New Zealand…
and eating balut in Manila.
[PEARL AND HAN BIN LAUGH]
Sir Han!
You and your world adventures.
You know what,
sometimes, I wonder
why you even chose
to stay here in Siargao.
You really love it that much?
Yes.
Very much.
[LOUD MUSIC PLAYING]
[HAN BIN CHUCKLES]
[HAN BIN SIGHS]
This is why
I lasted 10 years
and will go on for another
10 years and beyond!
[PEARL]
Hm...
You like the dancing?
No.
The celebration.
The celebration?
- Yeah.
- [PEARL CHUCKLES]
[HAN BIN]
See...
nobody celebrates
life better than Filipinos.
And I feel that more
here in Siargao.
Come to think of it,
maybe that’s the
real Siargao Curse.
People don’t leave the island
because they want to
celebrate life every day.
[HAN BIN] They celebrate
life through music.
They celebrate life
by enjoying the sea.
through family, friends.
They celebrate life through…
- [PEARL SIGHS]
- ...love.
[PEARL]
Thank you so much, Sir Han.
Thank you for
celebrating your
wonderful, mysterious,
and crazy life with us.
[HAN BIN AND PEARL LAUGH]
[PEARL SPEAKS SIARGAONON]
Thank you so much…
...for loving Siargao.
And most importantly,
thank you.
Because now,
I have something to
talk about in my essay.
You!
[PEARL LAUGHS]
- Me?
- [PEARL] Yes, you!
- [PEARL LAUGHS]
- No, no, no!
I...
You have to talk about
yourself in the essay.
That’s the whole point.
They want to know
your story.
Well, you’re part
of my story, Sir Han.
[USAD BY CUATRO]
- It’s beautiful, right?
- Yeah.
And your story’s beautiful, too.
Tell me more, okay?
[HAN BIN AND PEARL LAUGH]
What are you even doing?
Let’s go.
- [RECEPTIONIST] Later.
- Let’s go over there.
[RECEPTIONIST]
I’m busy, Kara.
- That can wait!
- Good evening, sir.
[MAN]
Um...
Do you have a
room available?
[RECEPTIONIST]
Sorry, sir.
[MAN]
Caitlyn?
Sorry, I don’t think
Kara wants to talk to you.
This is none of
your business, man.
[ARIEL] Mom!
I’ll handle this, okay?
You stay here.
I didn't know all of this.
[HAN BIN] When I met Kara,
she was already Kara.
How can you
not know, Sir Han?
[JAO]
Kara?
[KARA CRYING SOFTLY]
Why is he here?
Is he looking for me?
- Kara.
- [KARA BREATHES SHAKILY]
[CAROL]
It’s been over seven years.
Jao’s outside waiting for you.
You don’t have
to say anything.
[JAO] I just want you
to know that I’m here.
I thought I could fix it.
It doesn’t matter how
long it took you, you got out.
- [KARA CRYING SOFTLY]
- [JAO] You saved yourself.
So, please, Kara.
You have to forgive yourself.